## RABIAHUSSAIN

GRAPHIC DESIGNER

#### CONTACT

PHONE: 347 260-9477

- EMAIL:

rhussaindesigns@gmail.com

ADDRESS: New York, NY

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Creative individual with experience in graphic design. Specializes in digital and print design with a focus on brand identity and logo design.

Passionate about creating visually stunning and effective designs to help clients reach goals.

#### REFERENCES

Elaine Corso - Vertigo Media Group Marketing - Director (516) 312-4524 emvc28@gmail.com

Mark Smith - City College Professor (773) 677-3437

msmith4@ccny.cuny.edu

## WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO AND PROFILES

- rhussain.com
- behance.net/rhussain

#### EXPERIENCE

## Senior Graphic Designer

2022.04 - Present

Vertigo Media Group, Bohemia, NEW YORK

- Produced detailed illustrations for product packaging and promotional materials.
- Developed innovative designs for a variety of print and digital materials, including logos, brochures, websites, and advertisements.
- Coordinated communication between internal departments throughout entire project lifecycle.
- Incorporated animation elements into designs when necessary to enhance user experience.
- Mentored junior graphic designers in design principles and software applications.
- Ensured accuracy of all artwork before delivery by proofreading files against original specs.
- Developed strategies for brand identity across multiple channels.
- Completed creative deliverables within established deadline.
- Implemented creative strategies to enhance the visual appeal of marketing campaigns.

### Freelance Graphic Designer

2021.08 - 2022.02

LUNCHBOX TECH, US

- Developed and implemented creative visual solutions to meet client needs and objectives for branding campaigns.
- Combined design elements, text, photos and data into effective, elegant digital and print materials.
- Worked simultaneously on multiple projects and oversaw quality control on assigned projects.

#### **Design Tutor**

2014.02 - 2022.01

Research Foundation CUNY, New York, US

- Provided mentorship to students on how to effectively use Adobe Creative Suite applications such as Photoshop, InDesign, and Illustrator.
- Demonstrated advanced techniques in designing web interfaces using HTML5 and CSS3 coding standards.
- Assessed student projects and provided constructive feedback to improve their skills.
- Organized workshops for students to learn about the importance of branding, logo design, and identity systems.
- Developed interactive design tutorials for students to better

#### ART EXHIBIT

Solo exhibit called INTRICACIES at Tribeca Film Festival gallery.

The show displayed a collection of art depicting the use of intricate details and forms.

#### SKILLS

Illustrator InDesign Photoshop AfterEffects Figma HTML+CSS WordPress Squarespace **Constant Contact** Mailchimp Word Power Point Excel Self Motivated Observant Patient Highly Organized Leadership

- understand the concepts of graphic design and typography.
- Created and maintained warm and welcoming tutoring environment conducive to learning.

## Logo Designer

2020.04 - 2021.01

thisislaisa LLC, US

- Created the brand identity for thisislaisa brand and identity assets in Adobe Illustrator
- In addition, I expanded their brand identity with a stationery set for the sub brand This is Me, a scholarship program for young artists and students.

## Marketing Graphic Designer

2020.01 - 2020.12

Not a Riot, US

- Created social media content for the organization to promote a social movement
- Managed client website on Square Space and created promotional flyers and assist with research.
- Managed website updates utilizing WordPress as a Content Management System.
- Created logos, flyers, and other marketing materials.

#### Art Studio Assistant

2019.04 - 2019.12

Mimi Gross, New York, US

- Handled precision cutting of stencils based on the artist's design
- Accommodated on various printing methods, organizing and cutting different materials.
- Organized studio space by cataloging materials and supplies used in projects.
- Collaborated with artists on various projects, providing assistance with set-up, breakdown, and organization of art pieces.

#### **EDUCATION**

## The City College of New York,

Jun 2018

BA Digital Design GPA: 3.95

# Borough of Manhattan Community College,

Jun 2016

Completed coursework towards AS Multimedia Arts & Communication GPA: 3.92